<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>discrete blogarithm</title>
    <link>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on discrete blogarithm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>surveillance, whistleblowing, and security engineering</title>
      <link>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/surveillance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[Update (12/14/16): &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reuters.com/article/us-yahoo-nsa-order-idUSKCN12800D&#34;&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt; has specified that the rootkit was implemented as a Linux kernel module. Wow.]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday morning, Reuters dropped a news story revealing that Yahoo &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reuters.com/article/us-yahoo-nsa-exclusive-idUSKCN1241YT&#34;&gt;installed a backdoor&lt;/a&gt; on their own infrastructure in 2015 in compliance with a secret order from either the FBI or the NSA. While we all know that the US government routinely asks tech companies for surveillance help, a couple aspects of the Yahoo story stand out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The backdoor was installed in such a way that it was intercepting and querying all Yahoo Mail users&amp;rsquo; emails, not just emails of investigation targets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The program was implemented so carelessly that it could have allowed hackers to read all incoming Yahoo mail. Of course this also means FBI/NSA could have been reading all incoming Yahoo mail.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yahoo execs deliberately bypassed review from the security team when installing the backdoor. In fact, when members of the security team found it within weeks of its installation, they immediately assumed it had been installed by malicious hackers, rather than Yahoo&amp;rsquo;s own mail team. (This says something about what the backdoor code may have looked like.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yahoo apparently made no effort to challenge this overly-broad surveillance order which needlessly put hundreds of millions of users at risk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time this was happening, I was on the Yahoo Security team leading development on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yahoo/end-to-end&#34;&gt;End-to-End&lt;/a&gt; project. According to the Reuters report, the mail backdoor was installed at almost the exact same time that Alex Stamos and I &lt;a href=&#34;https://yahoo.tumblr.com/post/113708033335/user-focused-security-end-to-end-encryption&#34;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; the open-source launch of a Chrome extension for easy-to-use end-to-end encryption in Yahoo Mail at SXSW 2015. Ironically, if only we had been able to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2016/09/29/technology/yahoo-data-breach-hacking.html&#34;&gt;actually ship E2E&lt;/a&gt;, we would have given users a way to protect themselves from the exact backdoor scenario that they ended up in!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine for a moment that you are a security engineer who discovers a backdoor that your company execs have been trying to hide from your team. Would you quit on ethical grounds or stay so that you can prevent this from happening again? I don&amp;rsquo;t think there is one right answer. Personally I am grateful both for those who left and blew the whistle, and for those who stayed to protect Yahoo&amp;rsquo;s 800 million users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the job function of security engineers and pen testers is being ready for the moment you encounter something that you think should be disclosed but your company wants to keep secret. Think about what you would be willing to lose. Be prepared to escalate internally. Know the terms of your NDA and your exit agreement; try your best to honor them. Most of all, keep pushing for end-to-end encryption.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bus diaries</title>
      <link>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/bus-diaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/bus-diaries/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;While migrating my blog from WordPress to Hugo + GitHub Pages, I found two old diary entries from last autumn, a period of life when I rode buses a lot. They are copied below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;oct-28-2015&#34;&gt;oct 28, 2015&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;they told me not to, so i&amp;rsquo;m taking the bus from downtown LA to LAX. on my right, a man is asking everyone except me for 50 cents. everyone except me is a black guy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the bus stops for the zillionth time and a high schooler in a white t-shirt with some arm tattoos gets on. he sits down to my left and asks me what my arm tattoo is of. i start explaining particle physics. he asks what the hell i&amp;rsquo;m doing on the bus in LA. &amp;ldquo;hanging out,&amp;rdquo; i shrug. he thinks i am 19 years old and smart and beautiful and cool so he asks me out. i say sorry i live in san francisco, i am on my way to the airport, and just for the record, i am 24 years old. the guy next to him hears this and high-fives me because he used to live in oakland. the kid asks me if i could please change my flight so we can chill. i say no. then he says, &amp;ldquo;you are the dopest girl i&amp;rsquo;ve ever met. imma get off the bus and call my friend and tell him &amp;lsquo;bout you.&amp;rdquo; i say thanks. he remembers i&amp;rsquo;m not from south LA so he tells me it&amp;rsquo;s a real bad neighborhood and i should not talk to anyone if i get off the bus here. i say thank you, that information may be relevant to my immediate perambulations. the kid is obviously a bit sad we can&amp;rsquo;t hang out, so we say our goodbyes as he is getting off the bus to go to his friend&amp;rsquo;s house. i tell him he is young and i&amp;rsquo;m sure he will meet lots more people on the bus in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the guy from Oakland starts to play rap music at full volume on his phone. the man on my right leans over to him and whispers, &amp;ldquo;50 Cent?&amp;rdquo; i tell him, no sir, i believe this track is by Biggie. &amp;ldquo;that&amp;rsquo;s right,&amp;rdquo; he nods, as the guy from Oakland hands him 50 cents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;nov-11-2015&#34;&gt;nov 11, 2015&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;assuming you don&amp;rsquo;t have actual sleeping pills, the trick is to drink way too much alcohol the night before and then eat enough pasta in the morning before getting on the bus that you pass out as soon as you hit the highway. pasta is basically a date rape food, in case you somehow haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed. when you get on the bus, it&amp;rsquo;ll probably be half full of lonely-looking people with deep lines of weariness creased in their drooping faces. they shuffle onto the bus, reluctantly set their things in the adjacent seats, plug in their earbuds, and let their eyelids float down slowly like gentle sea creatures. the bus takes you from boston to new york city for just $14 and it only explodes catastrophically sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;before i pass out, i stare out the window at chunks of highway blurring by. it&amp;rsquo;s so fucking ugly here, you have no idea. the sky is the color of dirty dishwater. the sky pisses cold rain indiscriminately onto decrepit warehouses and rusty gas stations and weather-chipped rest stop signs creaking out their last desperate cries of dreary pretend-hospitality. it&amp;rsquo;s 3 in the afternoon and getting dark, which is such bullshit. really, nothing quite compares to the desolate feeling of sitting on a $14 bus surrounded by sad sleepy strangers while the feeble daylight dissolves into lonely darkness on a rainy afternoon in the middle-of-nowhere, connecticut (?). everyone obviously knows that the grip of winter is clenching tighter around their battered shoulders with every passing day now but nobody wants to talk about it. nobody wants to talk at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i hate it here. i miss it too. california turns everyone into sun-drenched polyester-clad ingrates, drunk on their own invincibility against the gentlest of elements. self-sufficiency is cheap in kind climates; rarely do you crave friendly company to pass the endless hours of icy drizzly darkness, nor do you exchange parsimoniously-heartfelt smiles of shared hardship with your neighbor while numbly stabbing your shovels into the frozen sidewalk. but when you wake up in the middle of the night to reach for a warm comforting hand that isn&amp;rsquo;t there, at least you&amp;rsquo;re not shivering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i probably should have had more pasta.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>xychelsea part 2</title>
      <link>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/xychelsea-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/xychelsea-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  The second and last time that I visit Chelsea Manning, we speak and move with a sense of urgency, as if a natural disaster is imminent. By now, the Ft Leavenworth prison visit procedure feels strangely familiar, like a movie you once watched in a dream. I check in with the uniformed officer at the Disciplinary Barracks&amp;#8217; front desk, wait uselessly while he misgenders Chelsea and figures out if I’m allowed to visit her, rent a locker to stow my jacket which is prohibited in the visit room (due to the having of zippers), don an unsuspicious smile when the guard tries to deny something i’m bringing (this time, it’s blank drawing paper and pencils &amp;#8211; both of which are eventually let through), pass through the metal detector and double-doored atrium, wait for the guard to let Chelsea through the opposite doors, hug briefly, sit down at her favorite table against the wall, buy her snacks from the vending machines twice (first course: Dr. Pepper and Sour Cream and Onion chips; second course: Pepsi and Doritos), watch the other inmates playing cards with their families, make jokes, laugh, cry, talk about computers and pretend we’re just normal friends doing friend-things, except we are forced to return to two separate worlds when the clock strikes 21:30.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  She tells me straight up that she was misty-eyed last night after my first visit and knows she’ll be bummed out for the next couple days after I leave. Trying to dispel the palpable gloom, I assure her that I’ll visit again, though I can’t promise when. It doesn&amp;#8217;t really work. The sadness is still there, swirling in the small grey room, so thick I can almost choke on it. Fortunately, we are both highly adept at changing the subject and pretending that everything is fine.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  I hand her a near-illegible list of questions for her from strangers on Twitter, which I had hurriedly compiled during the drive in. She brightens and grins, scrawling answers in the empty spaces as if it were a high school math exam.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_2168.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone wp-image-783&#34; src=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_2168-1024x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;questions for chelsea&#34; width=&#34;518&#34; height=&#34;518&#34; srcset=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_2168-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_2168-150x150.jpg 150w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_2168-300x300.jpg 300w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_2168-768x768.jpg 768w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_2168-624x624.jpg 624w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 518px) 100vw, 518px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  Q: Who do you support for president?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  A: [after pausing for a minute, explaining that she isn’t allowed to comment on this question.] I don’t like partisanship. [we chat about pitfalls of the two-party system.]
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  Q: Read any Kafka?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  A: yes!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  Q: Okies say hi!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  A: hi!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  Q: What do you hope people are doing [in response to your actions]?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  A: think for yourselves
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  Q: Are you comforted by [the knowledge of your] patriotism?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  A: &lt;flag-emoji&gt; USA!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  Q: What [do you do] to keep faith?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  A: pi
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  Q: What is the most interesting/exciting thing you’ve learned [in prison]?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  A: how to live collectively
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  Then she picks up another sheet of paper and mischievously says, “I should write some questions for Twitter in return.”
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_2169.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone wp-image-784&#34; src=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_2169-1024x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;questions from chelsea&#34; width=&#34;524&#34; height=&#34;524&#34; srcset=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_2169-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_2169-150x150.jpg 150w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_2169-300x300.jpg 300w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_2169-768x768.jpg 768w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/IMG_2169-624x624.jpg 624w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 524px) 100vw, 524px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  We spend a while chatting about small lighthearted things, like lip gloss quality (a subject on which her opinion is far more sophisticated than mine) and whether the red-orange powder on Doritos actually has any flavor (we agree the answer is no). Then abruptly we start to talk about hope, about her 35-year sentence, about the act of hanging on for as long as you can. Her eyes start to fill with tears.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  I tell her about all the people on the internet who care about her, all these people who she can’t see or talk to.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  Then I start to cry too.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  How many visitors do you have? I ask.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  Five, she says.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  We count them. There’s only four, including me. One of them has never actually visited. She doesn&amp;#8217;t know when her next visitor will be.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  Only friends and family who knew her pre-confinement are allowed. But that must be dozens if not hundreds of people, I think angrily to myself. Flights to Kansas City aren’t always cheap, but surely we could start a donation fund. My mind starts spinning, madly grasping for schemes to increase her visitor count. Sure, Leavenworth is a quiet boring little town, but rent is cheap and there’s nice hiking trails nearby. We could rent a vacation home and start a commune here with a bunch of her old friends. We’d take turns living here, we’d bring other people to keep us company, we would work and make art and host lectures during the day, we would visit her every night.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  I can tell that this would make her life so much more bearable. She jokes that maybe she would become too occupied with visits, that she wouldn&amp;#8217;t have time to do her classwork or write columns. A visit once a month would be nice, she says with a smile, but she thinks all her friends who knew her before are too afraid to see her, unwilling to bear the risk of being added to government watch lists. I reassure her that this will get better over time, that paranoia will fade faster than the last photographs the public has seen of her. My words sound empty to me.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  And then it&amp;#8217;s time to say our goodbyes. We hug as I tell her it’s not really goodbye (I’ll be back, I promise). The guard interrupts, yells at everyone that our time is really up. I try to look at her face, but it hurts to watch the tears come up again. I can tell that the next couple days will be tough.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  I pull her back for one last hug.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  Chelsea is a former soldier, a celebrated whistleblower, a role model for millions of people around the world, a pioneer for transgender rights, and a hero who will be remembered forever in American history, but right now she is just a small figure in my arms, scared like the rest of us and wanting nothing more than to go home.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  I walk out of the visitation room and she goes in the opposite direction back to her cell. For a single crystallizing moment, I play her movements in reverse and imagine her walking with me out of the prison. The guard is weary-eyed after three hours on his shift; he doesn’t notice a thing. Together, we pass quietly through the metal detector, walk down the stairs through the cold glass doors and onto the rain-soaked lawn where the night sky greets us with a starless nod. Barely a mile away, a cute Kansas town of smoke-filled bars, barbecue diners, and kitschy antique shops awaits us. Inside our chests floats a smiling thought of morning.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  Then she’s gone. My dream collapses into a hard knot of rage. Chelsea could walk twenty steps, through two doors, past a lone prison guard, and into a life of freedom. In reality, she can’t, because a vast and terrifying justice system stands in the way. Instead, she will spend up to 35 years in a remote prison cell, wishing she had more visitors. Some days she will wake up feeling motivated to conquer a new day. Other days she will wake up feeling like she wants to give up. The world will change around her, but life in the Ft Leavenworth Disciplinary Barracks will mostly stay the same, year after year.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  But for now she is doing her best, and her story is &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@xychelsea/far-from-over-b8c0f3246739#.mjggn8dqa&#34;&gt;far from over&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  [Update (5/27/16): Today marks the 6th anniversary of Chelsea&amp;#8217;s arrest. She&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@xychelsea/six-years-so-far-4dee0ee26fc8#.plys95uts&#34;&gt;written a letter&lt;/a&gt; to the world, and The Guardian has published a nice &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2016/may/27/chelsea-manning-six-years-prison-whistleblowing&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; about it.]
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>xychelsea</title>
      <link>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/xychelsea/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/xychelsea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  On the day that I am scheduled to see my friend Chelsea for the first time in six years, I wake up at 4:51pm to a shrieking fire alarm in my hotel room. Semi-conscious and disoriented, I leap out of bed and spin around wildly grabbing at all the things I care about &amp;#8211; my phone and passport, the precious slip of paper that will allow me entrance to Fort Leavenworth prison, the bag of quarters that Chelsea asked me to bring &amp;#8211; ready for an FBI raid disguised as a fire drill. Before I finish putting on shoes, the alarm stops. Slowly the wave of paranoia in my stomach grinds to a halt.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  I make myself be still and breathe for a moment, reabsorbing my surroundings. I’m standing on the fourth floor of a modest hotel on the edge of Fort Leavenworth, Kansas. Outside the window looms a blue-grey sky, a vast horizon dense and textured like charcoal mixed with cream. The land is flat, green, fertile, midwestern. A hot humid river is all that separates us from Missouri. To people like Chelsea and me, who grew up in Oklahoma and Missouri before running away to sharp-edged cities by the sea, this place feels simultaneously homelike and suffocating.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  As boring as Kansas is, you have to award it points for charm. Ex: a steakhouse across from the old Ft Leavenworth prison proudly proclaims itself “The Little Steak House Across from the Big House,” betraying no awareness of dark irony. The prison staff are all exceedingly polite and helpful, even when they are reprimanding me for not having a driver’s license, even when the receptionist mistakenly refers to Chelsea as “he” over a dozen times in a 5 minute phone call. “Now you go and have yourself a good day, honey,” they say in a warm-hued drawl as I navigate another step in the military bureaucracy, inching closer to actually being able to see Chelsea.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  For the curious, here is approximately the process I went through to gain visitation access to the Ft Leavenworth Disciplinary Barracks:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;December 2015&lt;/strong&gt;: Chelsea adds me to her list of telephone contacts and starts the application process for my visitation, which requires evidence that we were acquainted prior to her confinement.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;March/April 2016&lt;/strong&gt;: I receive a letter notifying me that my visitation was approved but a background check is required prior to the visit. Over the course of a week or two, I called at least five different offices at Fort Leavenworth to inquire about how to do the background check before flying to Kansas. Nobody really knew, so I gave up and just booked a flight.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;May 2016&lt;/strong&gt;: After confirming via phone that I was on the Fort Leavenworth visit schedule, I fly to Kansas City. My trip companions and I check in at the Visitor Control Center to register our vehicle and get access passes to the fort. One of us is denied for having a non-US passport. The other two of us are given passes promptly and without background checks. After that, the two of us are free to drive on and off the army base.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  If all goes well, I will be Chelsea’s first visitor since her sister in November.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  At 6:20pm on May 24, we drive into Fort Leavenworth for the first time. I am surprised to discover that it is full of grassy fields, lush tree-lined sidewalks, and pastel suburban houses, not at all like a place where you would put a military prison. I wave at some joggers.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  At 6:50pm, we finally find the United States Discipline Barracks, home of Chelsea’s prison cell. I walk inside and follow the signs to the visitation area. There are rules for visitation printed on the wall, which I’ve read a half-dozen times (no low-cut clothing, no short pants or skirts, 5 sheets of paper allowed, pencils and pens allowed, quarters and cash allowed in a transparent ziplock bag, no WiFi-enabled devices, no jackets, no cameras). The guard is friendly and makes light conversation with me, like all the Fort Leavenworth staff members I’ve interacted with so far. How bizarre to think that these friendly people, dripping with syrup-thick midwestern hospitality, are the same people keeping Chelsea forcibly isolated from the outside world for the next three decades.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  I force out a weak smile, explain my visitation purpose in my a faintly-artificial Missouri accent. The guard sees me on the visit schedule but is concerned that my shirt doesn’t have sleeves. Apparently sleeveless shirts are not allowed, even though this isn’t printed anywhere in the rules. Fuck. He goes to consult another officer. I nervously fidget.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  Thankfully, it is decided that I am allowed to enter (though I must wear a sleeved shirt next time). They let me through the metal detector after inspecting my 5 sheets of paper and ziplock bag containing 6 pencils, 1 pen, and $10 in quarters. I am flooded with relief, which quickly washes away into nervousness as I enter the visit room where Chelsea, my friend who I haven’t seen in six years, who I thought I would never see again after her arrest, is supposedly waiting.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  She’s not there. Instead there’s just some grey tables and chairs, depressingly few of which are occupied by inmates and their sad-looking visitors.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  And then the door opens and she walks in.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  We run towards each other.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  We hug, and my eyes fill with tears.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  When something that you’ve convinced yourself will never happen is finally happening, there’s a moment when your brain starts to panic and desperately record every detail, fearing that this is all an illusion that will soon dissolve without a trace. So I looked at her as if I would never see her again, my heart sinking with the realization that there will probably never exist a photo of Chelsea Manning, age 28, for the world to see. It made me sad, because she looks nothing like any of the photos of her on the Internet. She looked like a hero, brighter and stronger than in all my memories, radiant with a light that makes no sense.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  She was wearing a brown prison uniform that was too big for her small frame and smiling ear-to-ear. Her hair was neatly combed in a short pixieish cut, no longer than the 2-inch maximum allowed by the prison. Despite everything, she looked even younger than I remembered, with glowing skin and large blue eyes framed by elegant cheekbones. We beamingly smiled at each other for several seconds, suspended in disbelief and joy.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  “So do you wanna sit down?” I say. We find a table, and smile some more, and then I ask if she wants anything from the vending machines. “Sure, I’ll get something I’m not usually able to get,” she says, picking a Mountain Dew. I pay for it using 6 quarters from my ziplock bag. I also try to buy her some sour cream-flavored chips, but the snacks machine is broken, which makes me unusually angry. I make a mental reminder to ask the prison staff to fix it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  We sit back down and talk for most of two hours without pausing. We talk about life in prison, where she spends 40 hours a week working in a wood shop and somehow finds time to take college correspondence courses, read journals, write a column for The Guardian, and work with lawyers on her appeal. We talk about her growing interest in post-quantum cryptography and the collection of books building up in her cell. We talk about the last time we met and what our mutual friends are up to nowadays. We talk about our complex relationships with family. We talk about my shoes (which she likes a lot) and the kind of music that she used to DJ. We talk about where she would live if she weren’t in prison. We talk about how she find motivation to keep going every day, even though some days her life feels unfair and hopeless. Many times, I am speechlessly awed by her curiosity and perseverance in the face of extremely messed-up, depressing circumstances.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  I bring up her recent appeal to reduce her sentence from 35 years to 10 years, and she seems worried that it didn’t receive enough coverage in the press. She hopes that the world hasn’t forgotten about her.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  I’m not sure what to say. Like others, I feel guilty for not doing more to raise public awareness for her case. Maybe if I’d spoken up more about how her sentence was grossly unjust, or written about the importance of her trial as a precedent for all whistleblowers, she’d be in a better place now. Instead all I could do was sit and chat with her, drinking soda in a sterile grey room while someone’s toddler screamed and cried at the table next to us.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  Before I realize it, it&amp;#8217;s 9:25pm and the guard is yelling at us that our time is up. Chelsea, a self-identified extrovert, seems sad that I’m leaving, even though I’ll be back in 22 hours for my second and last day of visitation. We say our goodbyes and hug each other, holding the embrace longer this time.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  Back outside, I stand and watch the inmates’ families pile into their cars and drive home. Some of them live near the prison so they can visit their imprisoned loved one every day. I think about how strange it is that Chelsea is a hero to thousands if not millions of people, but there is nobody who does this for her. If she&amp;#8217;s lucky, she&amp;#8217;ll receive one more visit from a friend this year.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  I don’t want us to forget her at least.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  Update (5/26/16): Obligatory reminder that you can support Chelsea by donating to her &lt;a href=&#34;https://freedom.press/chelsea&#34;&gt;defense fund&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chelseamanning.org/learn-more/write-to-chelsea-manning&#34;&gt;writing her a letter&lt;/a&gt; (she reads every single one she receives), and following her accounts on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/xychelsea&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@xychelsea&#34;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;. In addition, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chelseamanning.org/resources/organizing-kit&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; has a nice toolkit for organizers to support her cause.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  Update (6/02/16): &lt;a href=&#34;https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/xychelsea-part-2&#34;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt; of this story is up for those who want to keep reading.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>25</title>
      <link>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/0x19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/0x19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  i turn 25 in an hour. this seems strange and unbelievable. surely 25 years of existence is enough to become acquainted with the monotonicity of time. but instead the seconds pass and disbelief stares back, unmoving.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  a quarter-century is a long time. with sadness, i realize how much of it i have forgotten already.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  imagine that we could live forever. would we still talk about wasting time if time were an unlimited resource? would we still apologize for being late?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  it seems that we should panic less about wasting time as our lifespan grows. paradoxically, every moment in time is unique and unrepeating, so we should be losing our shit over each precious second that passes.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  i used to imagine the movement of time as like a river, flowing by with the blended grace and strength of water and gravity. now it feels like a tired jogger limping by on a rhythmless gait, wrecked with joint pain and gasping for air. most steps are slogged with exhaustion, but every once in a while a wave of endorphins crashes in and makes the world spin with brightness.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;p1&#34;&gt;
  how unfortunate it is to be alive during the brief window of history when computers are getting faster just as your body is getting slower. i hope i’m lucky enough to become more of a computer soon.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>happy birthday</title>
      <link>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/happy-birthday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/happy-birthday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Chelsea,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You probably don&amp;#8217;t remember me, but we met in September 2009. This was before everyone knew your name and before many people knew mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was at home, helping my friend cut her hair. Out of the corner of my eye, I saw you walk into the living room. You were taking photos of our mural-covered walls, seemingly happy to be in such a bizarre and interesting house of MIT students. Someone introduced you to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That evening, or perhaps the evening after, I learned that you were a soldier training for Iraq. You wanted to leave the military someday and get a degree in Computer Science. You weren&amp;#8217;t much older than me, but you sounded more anxious and weary than anyone I&amp;#8217;d ever met before. We chatted for a while, and then I had to go finish my homework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You left Boston soon after that, and you friended me on Facebook. I accepted your friend request, and that was the last time we interacted with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you were arrested in 2010, I was proud of what you&amp;#8217;d done and angry at what happened to you after (I still am, every day). At the same time, the media &lt;a href=&#34;http://tech.mit.edu/V130/N30/wikileaks.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;started suspecting&lt;/a&gt; (baselessly) that friends of mine had assisted you in whistleblowing. For the first time in my life, I felt like I might be under more surveillance than the average 18 year-old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was then that I realized that although I hadn&amp;#8217;t done anything wrong, I had reason to be distrustful of the government that I lived under. I had nothing to hide, but nonetheless I was now part of a community under suspicion of a serious crime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started learning about security and privacy. Soon after, I installed PGP and started using it. Years later, I still think of you every time I help others encrypt their communications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So thanks for teaching me how to be paranoid. Thanks for showing me why everyone should care about surveillance, even if they aren&amp;#8217;t a whistleblower. Meeting you was an accident that could have happened to anyone. I&amp;#8217;m glad it happened to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy 28th Birthday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Yan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[PS for readers: You can help support Chelsea by donating to her legal defense team. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chelseamanning.org/press/chelsea-manning-defense-fund&#34;&gt;Info here.&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sniffly</title>
      <link>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/sniffly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/sniffly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every so often, I get sick of basically everything. Walls become suffocating, routine is insufferable, and the city I live in wraps itself against the sky like a cage. So inevitably I duck away and find something to chase (warm faces, the light in autumn, half-formed schemes, etc.), run until I&amp;#8217;m dizzy and lost and can&amp;#8217;t remember whose couch I&amp;#8217;m waking up on or why I crashed there. Weeks later, the sky bruises into swollen dusk, some familiar voice yells for me to come home so I run back into my bed once again, wondering if home is this place more than it is the feeling of staring at an unfamiliar timetable and noticing your heartbeat quicken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kinda happened last month so I took a 4 week leave (2 paid, 2 unpaid) from my job to read books, work on open source projects, and couchsurf the East Coast. I spent a lot of rainy days curled up on a friend&amp;#8217;s bed in Somerville, MA poking at my laptop, idle afternoons hiding in a corner of the MIT library poking at my laptop, and long electric evenings walking around New York City looking for a place to sit and poke at my laptop. A lot of laptop-poking happened while on &amp;#8220;vacation&amp;#8221; because I had promised some people that I would give two talks in October, one at &lt;a href=&#34;http://secretcon.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SecretCon&lt;/a&gt; and one at &lt;a href=&#34;http://sandiego.toorcon.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ToorCon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Predictably, I put off the ToorCon talk until 2 weeks ago. Also predictably, I started panicking and not sleeping anymore because I said I would show people a new browser fingerprinting technique which did not exist. Somehow, after a lot of head-banging-against-desk, I came up with one that sort-of worked about a week before the ToorCon and actually finished the code right before ToorCon. I named it &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/diracdeltas/sniffly&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sniffly&lt;/a&gt; because it sniffs browser history, and also because I was coming down with a cold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s how Sniffly works:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A user visits the Sniffly page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Their browser attempts to load images from various HSTS domains over HTTP. These domains were harvested from a scrape of HSTS domains in the Alexa Top 1M. It was really fun to write this scraper; I finally had a chance to use Python&amp;#8217;s Twisted!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sniffly sets a CSP policy that restricts images to HTTP, so image sources are blocked before they are redirected to HTTPS. This is crucial, because If the browser completes a request to the HTTPS site, then it will receive the HSTS pin, and the attack will no longer work when the user visits Sniffly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When an image gets blocked by CSP, its &lt;code&gt;onerror&lt;/code&gt; handler is called. In this case, the &lt;code&gt;onerror &lt;/code&gt;handler does some fancy tricks to semi-reliably time how long it took for  the image to be redirected from HTTP to HTTPS. If this time is on the order of a millisecond, it was an HSTS redirect (no network request was made), which means the user has visited the image&amp;#8217;s domain before. If it&amp;#8217;s on the order of 100 milliseconds, then a network request probably occurred, meaning that the user hasn&amp;#8217;t visited the image&amp;#8217;s domain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/sniffly/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a quick demo&lt;/a&gt;. It only works in recent Chrome/Firefox versions when HTTPS Everywhere is disabled. The results also turn up a lot of false positives if you are running an adblocker, since ad-blocked domains are indistinguishable from HSTS-blocked domains from a timing perspective. (However, since HTTPS Everywhere domains and ad-blocked domains are mostly the same for every user, they can simply be subtracted out to get more accurate results for users who run these browser extensions.) I didn&amp;#8217;t collect analytics on the site, but random testing with several friends showed a ~80% accuracy rate in the demo once browser extensions were accounted for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more info, check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/diracdeltas/sniffly&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;source code&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/presentations/toorcon2015.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ToorCon slides&lt;/a&gt; (pdf), and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kk2GkZv6Wjs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;talk recording&lt;/a&gt;. Someone submitted the demo to &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=10455735&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; and, to my horror, it was the #1 link for 6+ hours yesterday (!). I feel bewildered that this kind of attention is being granted (&lt;a href=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/backdooring-js/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;again&lt;/a&gt;) to random side projects that I do alone in my spare time, but I guess I should take whatever validation I can get right now. It would be sweet if people looked at my work and paid me to hack on interesting stuff for the public so i never had to work a real job again. Maybe someday it&amp;#8217;ll happen; until then I&amp;#8217;ll prolly hold down a day job and take more fake vacations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update: As of March 2016, Sniffly (CVE-2016-1617) has been fixed in the major browsers. Thank you Uncle Google for the bug bounty $$.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tbd</title>
      <link>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/tbd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/tbd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;you know things are getting better when you walk away from the hotel where you just gave two presentations wearing your best pretense of holding-it-togetherness while inside you felt shakey, hungover, and insane. remember how long you stood there, smiling and rationing weak handshakes while pretending you believed that you had a future? promise yourself you&amp;#8217;re never doing that again. you walk away from the volatile company of people who made you feel shitty about yourself without trying to and into the car of someone who looks like they could be your new friend. you drive down the street and pack your bags, take off your stupid clothes and pull on a grey tshirt. now you&amp;#8217;re driving down Highway 5 towards LA, the hills are honey-colored, the mountains crashing into sunset sky with symphonic grace, your insecurities start to crack like chipped gold paint. you pick at your wrecked fingernails and start to feel like you might have the vaguest idea of what to do with yourself tomorrow morning. then your new friend turns on the stereo and says, &amp;#8220;do you want to hear a song i wrote? it&amp;#8217;s about how my mom was a cunt.&amp;#8221; you say, sure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>backdooring your javascript using minifier bugs</title>
      <link>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/backdooring-js/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/backdooring-js/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In addition to unforgettable life experiences and personal growth, one thing I got out of DEF CON 23 was a copy of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.alchemistowl.org/pocorgtfo/&#34;&gt;POC||GTFO 0x08&lt;/a&gt; from Travis Goodspeed. The coolest article I&amp;#8217;ve read so far in it is &amp;#8220;Deniable Backdoors Using Compiler Bugs,&amp;#8221; in which the authors abused a pre-existing bug in CLANG to create a backdoored version of sudo that allowed any user to gain root access. This is very sneaky, because nobody could prove that their patch to sudo was a backdoor by examining the source code; instead, the privilege escalation backdoor is inserted at compile-time by certain (buggy) versions of CLANG.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That got me thinking about whether you could use the same backdoor technique on javascript. JS runs pretty much everywhere these days (browsers, servers, &lt;a href=&#34;http://postscapes.com/javascript-and-the-internet-of-things&#34;&gt;arduinos and robots&lt;/a&gt;, maybe even cars someday) but it&amp;#8217;s an interpreted language, not compiled. However, it&amp;#8217;s quite common to minify and optimize JS to reduce file size and improve performance. Perhaps that gives us enough room to insert a backdoor by abusing a JS &lt;em&gt;minifier.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;part-i-finding-a-good-minifier-bug&#34;&gt;Part I: Finding a good minifier bug&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Question: Do popular JS minifiers really have bugs that could lead to security problems?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Answer: After about 10 minutes of searching, I found one in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mishoo/UglifyJS2&#34;&gt;UglifyJS&lt;/a&gt;, a popular minifier used by jQuery to build a script that runs on something like &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.jquery.com/2014/01/13/the-state-of-jquery-2014/&#34;&gt;70% of the top websites&lt;/a&gt; on the Internet. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mishoo/UglifyJS2/issues/751&#34;&gt;bug itself&lt;/a&gt;, fixed in the 2.4.24 release, is straightforward but not totally obvious, so let&amp;#8217;s walk through it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UglifyJS does a bunch of things to try to reduce file size. One of the compression flags that is on-by-default will compress expressions such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;!a &amp;&amp; !b &amp;&amp; !c &amp;&amp; !d
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That expression is 20 characters. Luckily, if we apply &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/De_Morgan%27s_laws&#34;&gt;De Morgan&amp;#8217;s Law&lt;/a&gt;, we can rewrite it as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;!(a || b || c || d)
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which is only 19 characters. Sweet! Except that De Morgan&amp;#8217;s Law doesn&amp;#8217;t necessarily work if any of the subexpressions has a non-Boolean return value. For instance,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;!false &amp;&amp; 1
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;will return the number 1. On the other hand,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;!(false || !1)
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;simply returns true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if we can trick the minifier into erroneously applying De Morgan&amp;#8217;s law, we can make the program behave differently before and after minification! Turns out it&amp;#8217;s not too hard to trick UglifyJS 2.4.23 into doing this, since it will always use the rewritten expression if it is shorter than the original. (UglifyJS 2.4.24 patches this by making sure that subexpressions are boolean before attempting to rewrite.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;part-ii-building-a-backdoor-in-some-hypothetical-auth-code&#34;&gt;Part II: Building a backdoor in some hypothetical auth code&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cool, we&amp;#8217;ve found the minifier bug of our dreams. Now let&amp;#8217;s try to abuse it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s say that you are working for some company, and you want to deliberately create vulnerabilities in their Node.js website. You are tasked with writing some server-side javascript that validates whether user auth tokens are expired. First you make sure that the Node package uses uglify-js@2.4.23, which has the bug that we care about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next you write the token validation function, inserting a bunch of plausible-looking config and user validation checks to force the minifier to compress the long (not-)boolean expression:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;function isTokenValid(user) {
    var timeLeft =
        !!config &amp;&amp; // config object exists
        !!user.token &amp;&amp; // user object has a token
        !user.token.invalidated &amp;&amp; // token is not explicitly invalidated
        !config.uninitialized &amp;&amp; // config is initialized
        !config.ignoreTimestamps &amp;&amp; // don&#39;t ignore timestamps
        getTimeLeft(user.token.expiry); // &amp;gt; 0 if expiration is in the future

    // The token must not be expired
    return timeLeft &amp;gt; 0;
}

function getTimeLeft(expiry) {
  return expiry - getSystemTime();
}
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running &lt;code&gt;uglifyjs -c&lt;/code&gt; on the snippet above produces the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;function isTokenValid(user){var timeLeft=!(!config||!user.token||user.token.invalidated||config.uninitialized||config.ignoreTimestamps||!getTimeLeft(user.token.expiry));return timeLeft&amp;gt;0}function getTimeLeft(expiry){return expiry-getSystemTime()}&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the original form, if the config and user checks pass, &lt;code&gt;timeLeft&lt;/code&gt; is a negative integer if the token is expired. In the minified form, &lt;code&gt;timeLeft&lt;/code&gt; must be a boolean (since &amp;#8220;!&amp;#8221; in JS does type-coercion to booleans). In fact, if the config and user checks pass, the value of &lt;code&gt;timeLeft&lt;/code&gt; is always &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt; unless &lt;code&gt;getTimeLeft&lt;/code&gt; coincidentally happens to be 0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Voila! Since &lt;code&gt;true &amp;gt; 0&lt;/code&gt; in javascript (yay for type coercion!), auth tokens that are past their expiration time will still be valid forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;part-iii-backdooring-jquery&#34;&gt;Part III: Backdooring jQuery&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next let&amp;#8217;s abuse our favorite minifier bug to write some patches to jQuery itself that could lead to backdoors. We&amp;#8217;ll work with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/tree/1.11.3&#34;&gt;jQuery 1.11.3&lt;/a&gt;, which is the current jQuery 1 stable release as of this writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;jQuery 1.11.3 uses &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jquery/jquery/blob/1.11.3/package.json#L39&#34;&gt;grunt-contrib-uglify 0.3.2&lt;/a&gt; for minification, which in turn depends on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gruntjs/grunt-contrib-uglify/blob/v0.3.2/package.json#L30&#34;&gt;uglify-js ~2.4.0&lt;/a&gt;. So uglify-js@2.4.23 satisfies the dependency, and we can manually edit package.json in grunt-contrib-uglify to force it to use this version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are only a handful of places in jQuery where the DeMorgan&amp;#8217;s Law rewrite optimization is triggered. None of these cause bugs, so we&amp;#8217;ll have to add some ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backdoor Patch #1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First let&amp;#8217;s add a potential backdoor in jQuery&amp;#8217;s .html() method. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/diracdeltas/jquery/commit/e50c8ce26736027386aa7a698baeca7740a54a0b&#34;&gt;patch&lt;/a&gt; looks weird and superfluous, but we can convince anyone that it shouldn&amp;#8217;t actually change what the method does. Indeed, pre-minification, the unit tests pass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After minification with uglify-js@2.4.23, jQuery&amp;#8217;s .html() method will set the inner HTML to &amp;#8220;true&amp;#8221; instead of the provided value, so a bunch of tests fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-1.35.48-PM.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-670&#34; src=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-1.35.48-PM.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-08-23 at 1.35.48 PM&#34; width=&#34;844&#34; height=&#34;785&#34; srcset=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-1.35.48-PM.png 844w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-1.35.48-PM-300x279.png 300w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-1.35.48-PM-624x580.png 624w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 844px) 100vw, 844px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the jQuery maintainers are probably using the patched version of uglifyjs. Indeed, tests pass with uglify-js@2.4.24, so this patch might not seem too suspicious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-1.39.47-PM.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-671&#34; src=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-1.39.47-PM.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-08-23 at 1.39.47 PM&#34; width=&#34;1057&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; srcset=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-1.39.47-PM.png 1057w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-1.39.47-PM-300x80.png 300w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-1.39.47-PM-1024x272.png 1024w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-1.39.47-PM-624x166.png 624w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 1057px) 100vw, 1057px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cool. Now let&amp;#8217;s run grunt to build jQuery with this patch and write some silly code that triggers the backdoor:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;script src=&#34;../dist/jquery.min.js&#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;button&amp;gt;click me to see if this site is safe&amp;lt;/button&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;script&amp;gt;
        $(&#39;button&#39;).click(function(e) {
            $(&#39;#result&#39;).html(&#39;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;false!!&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&#39;);
        });
    &amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;div id=&#39;result&#39;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s the result of clicking that button when we run the pre-minified jQuery build:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-4.44.45-PM.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-672&#34; src=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-4.44.45-PM.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-08-23 at 4.44.45 PM&#34; width=&#34;511&#34; height=&#34;449&#34; srcset=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-4.44.45-PM.png 511w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-4.44.45-PM-300x264.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 511px) 100vw, 511px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As expected, the user is warned that the site is not safe. Which is ironic, because it doesn&amp;#8217;t use our minifier-triggered backdoor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s what happens when we instead use the minified jQuery build:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-4.45.10-PM.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-673&#34; src=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-4.45.10-PM.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-08-23 at 4.45.10 PM&#34; width=&#34;505&#34; height=&#34;465&#34; srcset=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-4.45.10-PM.png 505w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-4.45.10-PM-300x276.png 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 505px) 100vw, 505px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now users will totally think that this site is safe even when the site authors are trying to warn them otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backdoor Patch #2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first backdoor might be too easy to detect, since anyone using it will probably notice that a bunch of HTML is being set to the string &amp;#8220;true&amp;#8221; instead of the HTML that they want to set. So our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/diracdeltas/jquery/commit/a2092d8a85474c90e2e4d306a21a14af55365b58&#34;&gt;second backdoor patch&lt;/a&gt; is one that only gets triggered in unusual cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-7.48.14-PM.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-675&#34; src=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-7.48.14-PM.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-08-23 at 7.48.14 PM&#34; width=&#34;1020&#34; height=&#34;313&#34; srcset=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-7.48.14-PM.png 1020w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-7.48.14-PM-300x92.png 300w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-7.48.14-PM-624x191.png 624w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 1020px) 100vw, 1020px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, we&amp;#8217;ve modified jQuery.event.remove (used in the .off() method) so that the code path that calls &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.jquery.com/events/event-extensions/&#34;&gt;special event removal hooks&lt;/a&gt; never gets reached after minification. (Since &lt;code&gt;spliced&lt;/code&gt; is always boolean, its length is always undefined, which is not &amp;gt; 0.) This doesn&amp;#8217;t necessarily change the behavior of a site unless the developer has defined such a hook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say that the site we want to backdoor has the following HTML:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;script src=&#34;../dist/jquery.min.js&#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;button&amp;gt;click me to see if special event handlers are called!&amp;lt;/button&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;FAIL&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;script&amp;gt;
        // Add a special event hook for onclick removal
        jQuery.event.special.click.remove = function(handleObj) {
            $(&#39;div&#39;).text(&#39;SUCCESS&#39;);
        };
        $(&#39;button&#39;).click(function myHandler(e) {
            // Trigger the special event hook
            $(&#39;button&#39;).off(&#39;click&#39;);
        });
    &amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we run it with unminified jQuery, the removal hook gets called as expected:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-4.43.10-PM.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-677&#34; src=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-4.43.10-PM.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-08-23 at 4.43.10 PM&#34; width=&#34;705&#34; height=&#34;545&#34; srcset=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-4.43.10-PM.png 705w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-4.43.10-PM-300x232.png 300w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-4.43.10-PM-624x482.png 624w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 705px) 100vw, 705px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the removal hook never gets called if we use the minified build:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-4.43.42-PM.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-678&#34; src=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-4.43.42-PM.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-08-23 at 4.43.42 PM&#34; width=&#34;714&#34; height=&#34;544&#34; srcset=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-4.43.42-PM.png 714w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-4.43.42-PM-300x229.png 300w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Screen-Shot-2015-08-23-at-4.43.42-PM-624x475.png 624w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 714px) 100vw, 714px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously this is bad news if the event removal hook does some security-critical function, like checking if an origin is whitelisted before passing a user&amp;#8217;s auth token to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The backdoor examples that I&amp;#8217;ve illustrated are pretty contrived, but the fact that they can exist at all should probably worry JS developers. Although JS minifiers are not nearly as complex or important as C++ compilers, they have power over a lot of the code that ends up running on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s good that UglifyJS has added test cases for &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mishoo/UglifyJS2/blob/master/test/compress/issue-751.js&#34;&gt;known bugs&lt;/a&gt;, but I would still advise anyone who uses a non-formally verified minifier to be wary. Don&amp;#8217;t minify/compress server-side code unless you have to, and make sure you run browser tests/scans against code post-minification. [Addendum: Don&amp;#8217;t forget that even if you aren&amp;#8217;t using a minifier, your CDN might minify files in production for you. For instance, Cloudflare&amp;#8217;s collapsify &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cloudflare/collapsify/commit/e59253193282f2047eea1c770be57cb10c3c4a3a&#34;&gt;uses uglifyjs&lt;/a&gt;.]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, back to reading the rest of POC||GTFO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PS&lt;/strong&gt;: If you have thoughts or ideas for future PoC, please leave a comment or find me on Twitter (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bcrypt&#34;&gt;@bcrypt&lt;/a&gt;). The code from this blog post is up on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/diracdeltas/jquery&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Update 1: Thanks @joshssharp for posting this to Hacker News. I&amp;#8217;m flattered to have been on the front page allllll night long (cue 70&amp;#8217;s soul music). Bonus points &amp;#8211; the thread taught me &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=10108672&#34;&gt;something surprising&lt;/a&gt; about why it would make sense to minify server-side.]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Update 2: There is now a &lt;a href=&#34;https://lists.debian.org/debian-devel/2015/08/msg00427.html&#34;&gt;long thread&lt;/a&gt; about minifiers on debian-devel which spawned &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.debian.org/onlyjob/no-minification&#34;&gt;this wiki page&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=10146157&#34;&gt;another HN thread&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s cool that JS developers are paying attention to this class of potential security vulnerabilities, but I hope that people complaining about minification also consider transpilers and other JS pseudo-compilers. I&amp;#8217;ll talk more about that in a future blog post.]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>this blog uses Content Security Policy</title>
      <link>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/this-blog-uses-content-security-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/this-blog-uses-content-security-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;FYI: this post is an artifact of the Dark Ages when my blog was self-hosted WordPress. Let us not speak of that time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having recently given some &lt;a href=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/presentations/txjs2015.pdf&#34;&gt;talks&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3.org/TR/CSP/&#34;&gt;Content Security Policy&lt;/a&gt; (CSP), I decided just now to enable it on my own blog to prevent cross-site scripting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lil&amp;#8217; blog is hosted by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://scripts.mit.edu/&#34;&gt;MIT Student Information Processing Board&lt;/a&gt; and runs on a fairly-uncustomized WordPress 4.x installation. Although I could have enabled CSP by modifying my .htaccess file, I chose to use HTML &lt;meta&gt; tags instead so that these instructions would work for people who don&amp;#8217;t have shell access to their WordPress host. Unfortunately, CSP using &lt;meta&gt; hasn&amp;#8217;t landed in Firefox yet (&lt;a href=&#34;https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=663570&#34;&gt;tracking bug&lt;/a&gt;) so I should probably do the .htaccess thing anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s pretty easy to turn on CSP in WordPress from the dashboard:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;your\_blog\_path&gt;/wp-admin/theme-editor.php. Note that this isn&amp;#8217;t available for WordPress-hosted blogs (*.wordpress.com).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on Header (header.php) in the sidebar to edit the header HTML.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the start of the HTML &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; element, add a CSP meta tag with your CSP policy. This blog uses &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;meta http-equiv=&amp;quot;Content-Security-Policy&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;script-src &#39;self&#39;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; which disallows all scripts except from its own origin (including inline scripts). As far as I can tell, this blocks a few inline scripts but doesn&amp;#8217;t impede any functionality on a vanilla WordPress instance. You might want a more permissive policy if you use fancy widgets and plugins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Bonus points] You can also show a friendly message to users who disable javascript by adding a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;noscript&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; element to your header.&lt;a href=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Screen-Shot-2015-07-26-at-2.07.14-PM.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone wp-image-599 size-full&#34; src=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Screen-Shot-2015-07-26-at-2.07.14-PM.png&#34; alt=&#34;noscript&#34; width=&#34;1128&#34; height=&#34;381&#34; srcset=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Screen-Shot-2015-07-26-at-2.07.14-PM.png 1128w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Screen-Shot-2015-07-26-at-2.07.14-PM-300x101.png 300w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Screen-Shot-2015-07-26-at-2.07.14-PM-1024x346.png 1024w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Screen-Shot-2015-07-26-at-2.07.14-PM-624x211.png 624w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 1128px) 100vw, 1128px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fun fact I discovered during this process is that embedding a SoundCloud iframe will include tracking scripts from Google Analytics and scorecardresearch.com. Unfortunately CSP on the embedding page (my blog) doesn&amp;#8217;t extend to embedded contexts (soundcloud.com iframe), so those scripts will still run unless you&amp;#8217;ve disabled JS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Screen-Shot-2015-07-26-at-3.02.59-PM.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-600&#34; src=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Screen-Shot-2015-07-26-at-3.02.59-PM.png&#34; alt=&#34;scorecard&#34; width=&#34;806&#34; height=&#34;594&#34; srcset=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Screen-Shot-2015-07-26-at-3.02.59-PM.png 806w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Screen-Shot-2015-07-26-at-3.02.59-PM-300x221.png 300w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Screen-Shot-2015-07-26-at-3.02.59-PM-624x460.png 624w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 806px) 100vw, 806px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s all. I might do more posts on WordPress hardening later or even write a WP plugin (*shudders at the thought of writing PHP*). More tips are welcome too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE (8/24/15): CSP is temporarily disabled on this blog because Google Analytics uses an inline script. I&amp;#8217;ll nonce-whitelist it later and turn CSP back on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lessons from the ad blocker trenches</title>
      <link>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/lessons-from-the-ad-blocker-trenches/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/lessons-from-the-ad-blocker-trenches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Greetings from the beautiful museum district of Berlin, where I&amp;#8217;ve been trapped in a small conference room all week for the quarterly meeting of the W3C Technical Architecture group. So far we&amp;#8217;ve produced two documents this week that I think are pretty good:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2001/tag/doc/encryption-finding/&#34;&gt;no encryption backdoors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2001/tag/doc/unsanctioned-tracking/&#34;&gt;no non-consensual web tracking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just realized I have a few more things to say about the latter, based on my experience building and maintaining a semi-popular ad blocker (&lt;a href=&#34;https://eff.org/privacybadger&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Privacy Badger Firefox&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beware of ad blockers that don&amp;#8217;t actually block requests to tracking domains. For instance, an ad blocker that simply hides ads using CSS rules is not really useful for preventing tracking. Many users can&amp;#8217;t tell the difference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Third-party cookies are not the only way to track users anymore, which means that browser features and extensions that only block/delete third-party cookies are not as useful as they once were. This 2012 survey paper [&lt;a href=&#34;https://jonathanmayer.org/papers_data/trackingsurvey12.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;] by Jonathan Mayer et. al. has a table of non-cookie browser tracking methods, which is probably out of date by now: &lt;a href=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Screen-Shot-2015-07-17-at-4.32.55-PM.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-577&#34; src=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Screen-Shot-2015-07-17-at-4.32.55-PM.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2015-07-17 at 4.32.55 PM&#34; width=&#34;421&#34; height=&#34;684&#34; srcset=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Screen-Shot-2015-07-17-at-4.32.55-PM.png 421w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Screen-Shot-2015-07-17-at-4.32.55-PM-185x300.png 185w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 421px) 100vw, 421px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detecting whether a domain is performing third-party tracking is not straightforward. Naively, you could do this by counting the number of first-party domains that a domain reads high-entropy cookies from in a third-party context. However, this doesn&amp;#8217;t encompass reading non-cookie browser state that could be used to uniquely identify users in aggregate (see table above). A more general but probably impractical approach is to try to tag every piece of site-readable browser state with an entropy estimate so that you can score sites by the total entropy that is readable by them in a third-party context. (We assume that while a site is being accessed as a first-party, the user implicitly consents to letting it read information about them. This is a gross simplification, since first parties can read lots of information that users don&amp;#8217;t consent to by invisible fingerprinting. Also, I am recklessly using the term &amp;#8220;entropy&amp;#8221; here in a way that would probably cause undergrad thermodynamics professors to have aneurysms.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The browser definition of &amp;#8220;third-party&amp;#8221; only roughly approximates the real-life definition. For instance, dropbox.com and dropboxusercontent.com are the same party from a business and privacy perspective but not from the cookie-scoping or DNS or same-origin-policy perspective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hardest-to-block tracking domains are the ones who cause collateral damage when blocked. A good example of this is Disqus, commonly embedded as a third-party widget on blogs and forums; if we block requests to Disqus (which include cookies for logged-in users), we severely impede the functionality of many websites. So Disqus is too usability-expensive to block, even though they can track your behavior from site to site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hardest-to-block tracking methods are the ones that cause collateral damage when disabled. For instance, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.radicalresearch.co.uk/lab/hstssupercookies&#34;&gt;HSTS&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc7469#section-5&#34;&gt;HPKP&lt;/a&gt; both store user-specific persistent data that can be abused to probe users&amp;#8217; browsing histories and/or mark users so that you can re-identify them after the first time they visit your site. However, clearing HSTS/HPKP state between browser sessions dilutes their security value, so browsers/extensions are reluctant to do so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specifiers and implementers sometimes argue that Feature X, which adds some fingerprinting/tracking surface, is okay because it&amp;#8217;s no worse than cookies. I am skeptical of this argument for the following reasons:&lt;br clear=&#34;none&#34; /&gt;a. Unless explicitly required, there is no guarantee that browsers will treat Feature X the same as cookies in privacy-paranoid edge cases. For instance, if Safari blocks 3rd party cookies by default, will it block 3rd party media stream captures (which will store a unique deviceid) by default too?&lt;br clear=&#34;none&#34; /&gt;b. Ad blockers and anti-tracking tools like Disconnect, Privacy Badger, and Torbutton were mostly written to block and detect tracking on the basis of cookies, not arbitrary persistent data. It&amp;#8217;s arguable that they should be blocking these other things as soon as they are shipped in browsers, but that requires developer time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s all. And here&amp;#8217;s some photos I took while walking around Berlin in a jetlagged haze for hours last night:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/berlin1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone  wp-image-586&#34; src=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/berlin1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;berlin1&#34; width=&#34;391&#34; height=&#34;391&#34; srcset=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/berlin1.jpg 1080w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/berlin1-150x150.jpg 150w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/berlin1-300x300.jpg 300w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/berlin1-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/berlin1-624x624.jpg 624w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 391px) 100vw, 391px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/berlin2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone  wp-image-587&#34; src=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/berlin2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;berlin2&#34; width=&#34;392&#34; height=&#34;392&#34; srcset=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/berlin2.jpg 1080w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/berlin2-150x150.jpg 150w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/berlin2-300x300.jpg 300w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/berlin2-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/berlin2-624x624.jpg 624w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 392px) 100vw, 392px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update (7/18/15): Artur Janc of Google pointed out this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chromium.org/Home/chromium-security/client-identification-mechanisms&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;document by folks at Chromium&lt;/a&gt; analyzing various client identification methods, including several I hadn&amp;#8217;t thought about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pseudorandom podcast series, episode 1</title>
      <link>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/pseudorandom-podcast-series-episode-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/pseudorandom-podcast-series-episode-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The combination of my roommate starting a Rust podcast and a long, animated conversation with a (drunk) storyteller last night caused me to become suddenly enamored with the idea of starting my own lil&amp;#8217; podcast. Lately I keep thinking about how many spontaneous, insightful conversations are never remembered, much less entombed in a publicly-accessible server for posterity. So a podcast seemed like an excellent way to share these moments without spending a lot of time writing (I&amp;#8217;m a regrettably slow writer). I&amp;#8217;d simply bring folks into my warehouse living room, give them a beverage of their choice, and spend a leisurely hour chatting about whatever miscellaneous topics came to mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so, wasting no time, today I asked my ex-ex-colleague Peter Eckersley if he would like to be my first podcast guest. Peter runs the technology projects team at the Electronic Frontier Foundation and, more importantly, lives 3 blocks away from me. Fortuitously, Peter agreed to have me over for a chat later this afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I arrived, it turned out that one of Peter&amp;#8217;s housemates was having friends over for dinner, so finding a quiet spot became a challenge. We ended up in a tiny room at the back of his house where every flat surface was covered in sewing equipment and sundry household items. As Peter grabbed a hammer to reconstruct the only available chair in the room, I set up my laptop and fancy (borrowed) podcast microphone. We gathered around as close as we could and hit the record button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except for one hiccup where Audacity decided to stop recording abruptly, the interview went smoothly and didn&amp;#8217;t need much editing. Next time I&amp;#8217;ll plan to put myself closer to the mic, do a longer intro, and maybe cut the length down to 15 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/bcrypt/pseudorandom-podcast-episode-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Here is the result&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I had a fun time recording this podcast and am unduly excited about future episodes. Turns out a podcast takes ~10% of the time to write a blog post with the same content. 🙂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this and future episodes in the Pseudorandom Podcast Series, here&amp;#8217;s an &lt;a href=&#34;http://feeds.soundcloud.com/users/soundcloud:users:156877463/sounds.rss&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#8217;m going to reach SoundCloud&amp;#8217;s limit of 180 minutes real quick at this rate, so I will probably host these somewhere else in the future or start a microfunding campaign to pay $15/month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>life update</title>
      <link>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/life-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/life-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;i&amp;#8217;ve finally recovered enough from a multi-week bout of sickness to say some things and put up some photos. lately i&amp;#8217;ve felt exhausted and lethargic and unproductive to be honest. being sick probably had something to do with it; i sure hope next week gets better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;yesterday, someone told me they had a theory that everyone who sleeps at night (with rare exceptions) can only manage ~3 significant life events at a time. that sounds about right, but it feels like a lot has been going on. a partial, unordered list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;talked yesterday at the Yahoo Trust Unconference about &lt;a href=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/presentations/trust_unconference.html&#34;&gt;the future of email security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_558&#34; style=&#34;width: 423px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignnone&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/yan_sec.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;wp-image-558&#34; src=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/yan_sec.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;yan&#34; width=&#34;413&#34; height=&#34;413&#34; srcset=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/yan_sec.jpg 640w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/yan_sec-150x150.jpg 150w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/yan_sec-300x300.jpg 300w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/yan_sec-624x624.jpg 624w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 413px) 100vw, 413px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    photo credit Bill Childers
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;working on graceful degradation of hopes and feelings&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;writing software for Let&amp;#8217;s Encrypt as an EFF Technology fellow&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;trying to make sane w3c standards with these fine folks from the W3C Technical Architecture group&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_557&#34; style=&#34;width: 426px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignnone&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/TAG.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;wp-image-557&#34; src=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/TAG.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;TAG&#34; width=&#34;416&#34; height=&#34;416&#34; srcset=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/TAG.jpg 640w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/TAG-150x150.jpg 150w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/TAG-300x300.jpg 300w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/TAG-624x624.jpg 624w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 416px) 100vw, 416px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    photo credit Tantek Celik
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;packing bag(s) and moving to a new neighborhood (twice)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;finding balance on a skateboard and otherwise&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;I think emotional and crypto intelligence are severely underrated&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; spectator at the Yahoo Trust Unconference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rate-limiting anonymous accounts</title>
      <link>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/rate-limiting-anonymous-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/rate-limiting-anonymous-accounts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday TechCrunch &lt;a href=&#34;http://techcrunch.com/2015/03/02/twitter-tor-phone-verification/&#34;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; that Twitter now seems to be requiring SMS validation from new accounts registered over Tor. Though this might be effective for rate-limiting registration of abusive/spammy accounts, sometimes &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/the-switch/wp/2014/03/24/tor-usage-in-turkey-surges-during-twitter-ban/&#34;&gt;actual people&lt;/a&gt; use Twitter over Tor because anonymity is a prerequisite to free speech and circumventing information barriers imposed by oppressive governments. These users might not want to link their telco-sanctioned identity with their Twitter account, hence why they&amp;#8217;re using Tor in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are services like Twitter to do, then? I thought of one simple solution that borrows a popular idea from anonymous e-cash systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a 1983 paper, cryptographer David Chaum introduced the concept of blind signatures &lt;a href=&#34;http://techcrunch.com/2015/03/02/twitter-tor-phone-verification/&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;. A blind signature is a cryptographic signature in which the signer can&amp;#8217;t see the content of the message that she&amp;#8217;s signing. So if Bob wants Alice to sign the message &amp;#8220;Bob is great&amp;#8221; without her knowing, he first &amp;#8220;blinds&amp;#8221; the message using a random factor that is unknown to her and gives Alice the blinded message to sign. When he unblinds her signed message by removing the blinding factor, the original message &amp;#8220;Bob is great&amp;#8221; &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; has a valid signature from Alice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may seem weird and magical, but blinded signatures are actually possible using the familiar RSA signature scheme. The proof is straightforward and on Wikipedia so I&amp;#8217;ll skip it here &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/the-switch/wp/2014/03/24/tor-usage-in-turkey-surges-during-twitter-ban/&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;. Basically, since RSA signatures are just modulo&amp;#8217;d exponentiation of some message &lt;em&gt;M&lt;/em&gt; to a secret exponent &lt;em&gt;d&lt;/em&gt;, when you create a signature over a blinded message &lt;em&gt;M&amp;#8217; = M*r^e&lt;/em&gt; (where &lt;em&gt;r&lt;/em&gt; is the blinding factor and &lt;em&gt;e&lt;/em&gt; is the public exponent), you also create a valid signature over &lt;em&gt;M&lt;/em&gt; thanks to the distributive property of exponentiation over multiplication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the existence of blind signature schemes, Twitter can do something like the following to rate-limit Tor accounts without deanonymizing them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Say that @bob is an existing Twitter user who would like to make an anonymous account over Tor, which we&amp;#8217;ll call @notbob. He computes &lt;em&gt;T = H(notbob) * r^e mod N&lt;/em&gt;, where &lt;em&gt;H&lt;/em&gt; is a hash function, &lt;em&gt;r&lt;/em&gt; is a random number that Bob chooses, and &lt;em&gt;{e,N}&lt;/em&gt; is the public part of an Identity Provider&amp;#8217;s RSA keypair (defined in step 2).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bob sends &lt;em&gt;T&lt;/em&gt; to an identity provider. This could be Twitter itself, or any service like Google, Identica, Facebook, LinkedIn, Keybase, etc. as long as it can check that Bob is probably a real person via SMS verification or a reputation-based algorithm. If Bob seems real enough, the Identity Provider sends him S&lt;em&gt;ig(T) = T^d mod N = H(notbob)^d * r mod N&lt;/em&gt;, where &lt;em&gt;d&lt;/em&gt; is the private part of the Identity Provider&amp;#8217;s RSA keypair.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bob divides &lt;em&gt;Sig(T)&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;em&gt;r&lt;/em&gt; to get &lt;em&gt;Sig(H(notbob))&lt;/em&gt;, AKA his Identity Provider&amp;#8217;s signature over the hash of his desired anonymous username.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bob opens up Tor browser and goes to register @notbob. In the registration form, he sends &lt;em&gt;Sig(H(notbob))&lt;/em&gt;. Twitter can then verify the Identity Provider&amp;#8217;s signature over &amp;#8216;notbob&amp;#8217; and &lt;strong&gt;only&lt;/strong&gt; accept @notbob&amp;#8217;s account registration if verification is successful!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that this achieves some nice properties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every anonymous account is transitively validated via SMS or reputation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ignoring traffic analysis (admittedly a big thing to ignore), anonymous accounts and the actual identities or phone numbers used to validate them are unlinkable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thoughts? I&amp;#8217;d bet that someone has thought of this use case before but I couldn&amp;#8217;t find any references on the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techcrunch.com/2015/03/02/twitter-tor-phone-verification/&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hit.bme.hu/~buttyan/courses/BMEVIHIM219/2009/Chaum.BlindSigForPayment.1982.PDF&#34;&gt;http://www.hit.bme.hu/~buttyan/courses/BMEVIHIM219/2009/Chaum.BlindSigForPayment.1982.PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/the-switch/wp/2014/03/24/tor-usage-in-turkey-surges-during-twitter-ban/&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blind_signature#Blind_RSA_signatures.5B2.5D:235&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blind_signature#Blind_RSA_signatures.5B2.5D:235&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>canvas #1</title>
      <link>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/canvas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://diracdeltas.github.io/blog/canvas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/painting2.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-538&#34; src=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/painting2.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;painting2&#34; width=&#34;887&#34; height=&#34;596&#34; srcset=&#34;https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/painting2.jpeg 887w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/painting2-300x202.jpeg 300w, https://zyan.scripts.mit.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/painting2-624x419.jpeg 624w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 887px) 100vw, 887px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;that could have been us&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, 2015&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oil pastels, lipstick, eyeliner, cold medicine, and ballpoint pen on canvas.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i painted this while standing in my bathroom on valentine&amp;#8217;s day&amp;#8217;s night, unable to sleep and grotesquely feeling the weight of the oncoming dawn. it was my first time drawing on canvas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;as i worked, i kept thinking about all these people passing to and from doomed relationships, that feeling of being stupidly and everlastingly perched on the brink between hope and mutilation. that&amp;#8217;s more or less what this is about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>