<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cryptography on discrete blogarithm</title>
    <link>https://blog.azuki.vip/tags/cryptography/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cryptography on discrete blogarithm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.azuki.vip/tags/cryptography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Some thoughts on the NSA and elliptic curve cryptography</title>
      <link>https://blog.azuki.vip/some-thoughts-on-the-nsa-and-elliptic-curve-cryptography/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.azuki.vip/some-thoughts-on-the-nsa-and-elliptic-curve-cryptography/</guid>
      <description>Below is an amalgamation of some posts that I made recently on a popular microblogging platform:
========
I’ve been reading a lot today about what I believe is a super-likely NSA backdoor into modern cryptosystems.
There are these things called elliptic curves that are getting used more and more for key generation in cryptography, especially in forward-secrecy-enabled SSL (which is the EFF-recommended way to secure web traffic). The problem is that the choice of parameters for the elliptic curves most used in practice are set by NIST, and we know for sure that the NSA has some influence on NIST standards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some thoughts on Facebook implementing forward secrecy</title>
      <link>https://blog.azuki.vip/some-thoughts-on-facebook-implementing-forward-secrecy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.azuki.vip/some-thoughts-on-facebook-implementing-forward-secrecy/</guid>
      <description>Last month, CNET announced that Facebook is working on implementing a property called forward secrecy in its encryption of user data. The article is pretty long, but the gist of it is:
Forward secrecy is good news, at least theoretically. Right now, when you send data to Facebook’s servers, your data gets encrypted so that someone who intercepts your data can’t read it unless they have Facebook’s secret key. However, if an eavesdropper is recording your messages now and somehow gets the secret key in the future, they can go back and decrypt all your encrypted communications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
