<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SSL on discrete blogarithm</title>
    <link>https://blog.azuki.vip/tags/ssl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SSL on discrete blogarithm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.azuki.vip/tags/ssl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The most subtle joke I’ve made all year</title>
      <link>https://blog.azuki.vip/the-most-subtle-joke-ive-made-all-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.azuki.vip/the-most-subtle-joke-ive-made-all-year/</guid>
      <description> Dan Auerbach: Any doctor can prescribe any medication to anyone. That is a broken system. Yan: Medication needs to be able to do doctor-pinning. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summertime, and the HTTP traffic sniffing is easy</title>
      <link>https://blog.azuki.vip/summertime-and-the-http-traffic-sniffing-is-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.azuki.vip/summertime-and-the-http-traffic-sniffing-is-easy/</guid>
      <description>So it happens that every time you access a URL that starts with “http://”, anyone on your local network can see what you’re doing with almost no effort worth writing about. This includes the page itself as well as any information that you’re transferring, like credit card numbers and passwords (which are hopefully encrypted). It’s worth reiterating that this isn’t difficult at all, even if your network is WPA2-protected, as most supposedly-secure WiFi networks are nowadays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some thoughts on Facebook implementing forward secrecy</title>
      <link>https://blog.azuki.vip/some-thoughts-on-facebook-implementing-forward-secrecy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.azuki.vip/some-thoughts-on-facebook-implementing-forward-secrecy/</guid>
      <description>Last month, CNET announced that Facebook is working on implementing a property called forward secrecy in its encryption of user data. The article is pretty long, but the gist of it is:
Forward secrecy is good news, at least theoretically. Right now, when you send data to Facebook’s servers, your data gets encrypted so that someone who intercepts your data can’t read it unless they have Facebook’s secret key. However, if an eavesdropper is recording your messages now and somehow gets the secret key in the future, they can go back and decrypt all your encrypted communications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
